#Encodergasm Presents
～
（ゲートアナウンス）
間もなく 当210便は
金星に到着いたします
Soon, this flight 210 will arrive on Venus.
金星のテラフォーミングに
用いられております浮遊植物は―
Some people may have an allergic reaction to...
...the floating plants used in the terraforming of Venus.
一部のお客さまにアレルギー症状を
起こさせることがございます
It has a chance of degenerating into Venus-sickness...
金星病に悪化する場合も
ございますので―
異常が現れた場合は―
...so if symptoms appear, please consult a doctor immediately.
早急に専門の医師による診察を
お受けください
（乗客の悲鳴）
（ルーイ）静かにしたまえ 諸君
Quiet down, everyone!
Both hands behind your heads!  All of you!
全員 両手を頭の後ろで組め
I-I'll give you money!
か 金なら出す
私だけでも降ろしてくれ
I don't care about the others, let me off...
Anyone who makes a ruckus ends up like him!
（デューイ）騒ぐやつは こうよ
Dammit... why did this have to be the day...
（ロコ）やべえ
何だってこんなときに
You over there!
（ヒューイ）おい そこ！
HEY!
おい！
You listening to me?!
聞こえてんのか こら！ てめえ
You!  Get up!
起きろ！
（スパイク）う うん？
Alright.
よーし
おとなしく両手を頭の後ろで…
Quietly put both hands behind your head...
Hey!  Don't fall asleep!
おい！ 寝るな
俺たちが誰だか分かってんのか？
Who the hell do you think we are?!
YOU!
てめえ！
ぐああっ
Whoops, sorry.
ああ こりゃあ失礼
（デューイ）そこまでよ！
That's enough!
Enough of YOU, Ms.  Bounty.
（フェイ）そっちがね
賞金首さんたち
（ロコ）ばか言うなよ！
これが5000だって？
Don't be silly!
This is 5000?!
特別料金だよ
Special price.
そんなの どこにも
書いてねえじゃねーか！
That's not written anywhere up there!
大体あそこは住居じゃないんだよ
But it's not to normal residential quarters.
I'm asking ya for a favor here...
なあ 頼むよ　そこを何とかさ
All the way out there to the middle of the desert...
わざわざ
あんな砂漠くんだりまで…
Hey!  Don't rip me off here!
おい！ ぼるんじゃねえよ
ちょっ ちょっと 君
W-Wait a minute...
ちゃんと届けろよ？ いいな
Make sure it gets there!  Got that?!
ああ おい
Hey, wait!
Thanks for the business.
まいどあり
Hi.
はーい
なんだ？
What?
My share.
分け前
Here?
ここでか？
I need it now.
今すぐ入り用なの
That's all you get.
お前の金は それで全部だからな
I know that!
分かってるわよ
Depositing it at the casino again?
またカジノに預金か？
It's better than a bank!
（フェイ）銀行よか マシでしょ
はっ 懲りねえやつ
She never gives up...
（ロコ）
うおっ おっとっとっと　うっ
どわっ
ひったくりだったら間に合ってるぜ
I don't need any more pickpockets.
（ロコ）フフッ フフフフフ
すげえ
Amazing...  You're really amazing!
やっぱり すげえや
へっヘヘヘ
あんた さっき すげえ技で―
You're the one that rounded up the hijackers with some amazing moves, right?
ハイジャックの犯人を
のしちゃった人だろ？
なあ 頼みがあるんだ
I have a favor to ask.
さっきの技 俺にも教えてくれよ
Can you teach me how to move like that?
柔道かい？ クンフーかな？
はあっ　ほー
Is it judo?  Or kung-fu?
Hey, wait a minute.
（ロコ）
なあ ちょっと待ってくれよ
I want to be strong, like you.
俺 あんたみたいに
強くなりてえんだよ
（スパイク）しつこいやつだな
駄目ったら駄目だ
You're an annoying guy...
A no is a no.
いいだろ？ ちょっとぐらい
頼むよ 師匠
Oh, come on.  Just a little.  Please, master!
Please!
Hey, wait a sec!
ああ ちょっと！
What was with that guy?
何なんだ？ あいつは
え？ な なあ ちょっと
C-Come on, just a little bit.  Think of it as helping me.
いや 助けると思ってさ
情けぐらいあるだろ？
You got a little bit of mercy in ya, right?
今 切らしてる
I'm out of that right now.
Come on, please, it's not like you're losing anything.
（ロコ）なあ 頼むよ
減るもんじゃないんだしさ
Quit it already?!
いい加減にうせ… うっ？
Venus has a lot of helium in the atmosphere.
金星はヘリウムが多いんだ
薬を飲めばすぐ治るよ
You can fix it quickly with some medicine.
Come on, that's not fair!  Man!
そ そっ そりゃねえよ！ なあ
You're the one that...
お前が勝手に…
（スパイク）うっ うん？
（ロコ）フフフフフフ
That was just a throat drop.
さっきのは のどあめ
You!
（スパイク）てめー！
Oh!  Hands-on training?
おっ 実戦訓練かい？
よっ はあっ てやあっ ほおい
You're...
お前…
I'm Roco Bonnaro.  Nice meeting you, master!
俺 ロコ･ボナーロ
よろしく 師匠
Our first income in a while.
（ジェット）久しぶりの収入だ
I'll feed you something good.
うまいもん食わしてやるからな
This is all thanks to the mastermind.
やっぱ参謀の腕だな こりゃ
And next up...
お次のネタは と
（男性）ああっ
I'm telling you to not tense up!
（スパイク）
力を入れるなって言ってるんだ
（ロコ）いや そうしねえと
相手を倒せねえじゃねえか
But you can't defeat enemies that way.
The flow is more important... not power.
（スパイク）大事なのは流れだ
力じゃない
（ロコ）えっ？
You have to be like the water.
（スパイク）
水のようになるんだよ
You get it?
分かるか？
Not one bit.
（ロコ）全然 分かんね
（スパイク）そうだよな
よし ナイフで かかってきてみろ
That's what I thought.
All right, come after me with a knife.
（ロコ）ケガするぜ
You'll get hurt.
Just do it.
（スパイク）いいから
All right, here I come!
んじゃ いくぜ！
What's going on?
どうなってるんだ？
I'm not tensing up anywhere.
（スパイク）
どこにも力なんか入れてない
お前の無駄な力を利用しただけだ
I'm just using your excessive force.
I control the flow of power...
力の流れを
コントロールするんだよ
...and to do that, I have to relax the whole body...
そのためには―
どんな動きにも対応できるように
全身の力を抜いて―
...to be able to react to any movement.
そう 水みたいになるってことだ
Yeah...
I become like water.
Water?
水？
Yeah.
そう　水は
どんな形にもなれるし―
Water can take any form.
It can flow along slowly or beat down aggressively, right?
ゆっくり流れることも
激しく打つこともできるだろ？
分かったような
分からねえような…
I dunno if I get it or not...
（じいさん）おい
年寄りは大事にするもんじゃ！
You should take care of your elders!
Here, hold this!
（ロコ）これ 頼む
（スパイク）ああ？
Tonight...  No, tomorrow night.
今晩 いや 明日の夜
町はずれの聖堂で！
At the cathedral on the outskirts of this town!
Hey, wait!!
おい！ 待てよ
There he is!  Don't let him get away!
（ピカロの一味）
いたぞ！ 逃がすな
Casino?
（ジェット）カジノだと？
The ones around here are famous for being stingy...
ここいらのは
渋いんで有名だってのによ
Don't worry about it.  It's not our money.
気にすんなよ　人の金だ
On top of it, she takes off like a bullet and we don't know when she gets back.
おまけに鉄砲玉で―
いつ戻ってくるか
知れたもんじゃねえ
Hey, no use wasting time.  How about making some pocket cash?
なあ 時間を無駄にする手はねえ
小遣い稼ぎってのはどうだ？ ん？
ピカロ･カルヴィーノ
Piccaro Calvino.
Usually a stingy little thief, but went in big this time.
けちな盗っ人だが―
今回は ちょっと気張ったのか
デカいもん盗みやがった
Price is doubled if we get the whole crew.
一味で捕まえりゃあ 倍額だ
盗まれたのが こいつだ
And this is the stolen goods.
It makes the remedy for Venus-sickness, but apparently it's...
金星病の特効薬なんだが―
栽培が難しくて
うん千万の値打ちもんらしい
...hard to grow them and they're worth tens of millions.
（ロコ）ごめんよ！
Sorry!
くっそー どこ行きやがった？
Shit, where did he go?
えー くそっ
逃げ足だけは早いやつだ
Shit, he's sure good at running.
へっへーんだ　おっ
I say we take it.  I mean, it's worth much more than nabbing that group.
ネコババしちゃえば いいじゃない
そんな一味 捕まえるより
よっぽど もうけなんだし
No, we can't!
いや 駄目だ
Hey, you thought for a moment!
あっ 今 間があった
Idiot!  It's better to not be involved with dangerous stuff like this!
ばか野郎　やばいブツには
手を出さないほうが正解だ
It's okay if they don't find out, right?
ばれなきゃいいんでしょ？
カジノでいくらすったんだ？
So, how much did you lose at the casino?
何よ
What?
ピカロは任せた　俺はロコを追う
I'll leave Piccaro up to you.  I'm going after Roco.
（フェイ）えっ 待ってれば？
どうせ会うのに
Why don't you wait?  You're gonna see him anyway.
賞金の女神には
前髪しかねえっていうだろ？
They say that Lady Bounty only has bangs.
幸運の女神でしょ
You mean Lady Luck.
Remains of a shuttle?  Why in such a place?
（ジェット）シャトルの残骸？
何だって そんなところに？
Dunno...
（スパイク）さあな
There might be some weirdos that do live out in the desert, but still...
（ジェット）わざわざ砂漠に住む
物好きもいるかもしれねえが
それにしても
Don't move!
（ステラ）動かないで！
動かないで　両手を挙げて
Don't move!  Both hands up!
（スパイク）怪しいもんじゃない
なんて言うと余計 怪しいか
I'm nobody suspicious...
That makes me sound even more suspicious, doesn't it?
Who are you?  Why are you here?
誰なの？ どうして ここに？
Answer me!
答えて！ ああっ
Let go.
離して
I just came here to see Roco...
俺は ただ
ロコに会いに来ただけで…
ロコのお友達？
You're...  Roco's friend?
えっ あ いや…
Huh?  Um, no...
I'm glad...
よかった
Hey, make sure you wash your hands.
おい ちゃんと手 洗えよ
We can't find him, Boss.
ボス やっぱり見つかりませんぜ
は はあい
H-Hi...
You know, it's all because of those floating plants.
（ステラ）
ほら 空に浮いてる あの植物
あのせいなの
Sometimes they send spores that look like snow.
ごくたまに
まるで雪みたいな胞子を降らせるの
Most people are fine, but my body isn't... and my eyes...
普通の人は大丈夫らしいんだけど
あたしは体質のせいで目が
（スパイク）不便じゃないか？
Isn't it inconvenient?
No.  It's not a big deal once you get used to it.
（ステラ）ううん
慣れれば どうってことないわ
Besides...
それに 見えないほうが
分かることだってあるのよ
Sometimes you understand more when you can't see.
You'll get better, right?
治るんだろ？
If I put money into it...
（ステラ）お金をかければね
あたしは別に
このままでもいいんだけど―
I don't mind staying as is... but Roco...
ロコが
妹思いなんだな
He cares about his little sister.
これ 昨日ロコが送ってくれたの
Roco sent me this yesterday.
Everyone says bad things about him...
（ステラ）みんな
ロコのことを悪く言うけど…
And he seems to hang out with some bad people...
確かに
悪い仲間はいるみたいだけど―
But Roco is a good person.
ロコは いい人なのよ
（スパイク）俺も その悪い仲間の
一人かもしれないぜ？
I might be one of those bad people he hangs out with.
Maybe.  Maybe you are.
そうね　そうかもしれない
But you're different.
でも あなたは違うわ
I can tell.
あたしには分かるの
Both you and Roco have something beautiful deep in you.
ロコもあなたも
ひどく分かりにくいけど―
It's hard to tell, but it's there.
きれいなものを持ってる
I can see it.  That's why I'm offering you tea like this.
それが分かったから
こうしてお茶を出してあげてるのよ
Something beautiful, huh?
（スパイク）“きれいなもの”か
I probably lost that long, long ago...
そいつは多分
ずっと昔になくしちまったな
見せたかったぞ
I want to see Piccaro.  Tell me where he is.
（フェイ）ピカロに会いたいの
居場所を教えて
What?  I don't know who that is.
何？ 知らねえなあ そんなもの
Can you remember?
思い出せる？
あ 思い出した
I-I remember now!
What did you just say?
ああ？ 何てった？
グレイアッシュの種の値段？
The price of a gray ash seed?
I'm just asking.
（スパイク）聞いてみただけだ
Don't be a fool.  Those things are like gems.
（ジェット）
ばか言え　ありゃ もはや宝石だ
拝めたらラッキーってやつだ
You're lucky if you ever see one...
（スパイク）へえー
Well, it might be difficult to sell them once you get them...
（ジェット）
まあ 実際に売りさばくとなると
難しいだろうが―
...but I would say 8 million each.
それでも１粒 800万か そこらは…
You got some?!
手に入れたのか？
No...
（スパイク）いや
Thought not...
（ジェット）だろうな
How about Piccaro?
ピカロのほうは？
Oh, just a little more.
（ジェット）ああ もうちょいだ
そっちも うまくやれよ
Don't screw up on your end.
So, little Roco.
（ピカロ）さーて ロコ君よ
You can be nice and tell us where the pot is.
おとなしく
鉢のありかを教えるならよし
If you don't want to tell us...
教えたくないなら…
Sorry.  I dropped it.
わりいな　落としたんだ
That ain't gonna work, is it?
なーんてのじゃ 駄目？
ううっ ああ…
My little Roco.
ロコ君よ
I've heard that you have a little sister.
聞くところによると
妹がいるらしいじゃないか
She has nothing to do with this!
妹は関係ない！
フッフー
じゃ 一体どこにあるのかな？
Oh, really?  Then where is it?
I-It's...
そ それは…
I want to see Piccaro.  Tell me where he is.
ピカロに会いたいの
居場所を教えて
ほんがっ えれえええ あっ
H-Hyu don'f haff to be so suhhen...
Huh?  Where did you say?
何？ どこだって？
I can'f breef...
はいおひいい
Yo.
（スパイク）よう
（ロコ）あっ
O-Oh, you're here.
ああ 来てくれたんだな
ちゃんと持ってきたぜ
And I brought it, like you told me to.
Sorry, but I snuck a peek inside.
悪いが中を見せてもらった
（ロコ）それが何か分かったのか？
You know what it is?
Grey ash.  Something spectacular unlike its name.
（スパイク）グレイアッシュ
名前の割には大した代物だ
何しろ お前たちの賞金の
ざっと10倍だからな
I mean, it's worth 10 times the bounty placed on all of you.
You're a bounty hunter, aren't you?
あんた 賞金稼ぎなんだな？
俺を捕まえるために来たのか？
Are you here to nab me?
ステラには
こいつが必要なんだろ？
Stella needs this, right?
Run, or you'll be killed!
逃げるんだ！ あんた殺されるよ
（フェイ）何よ　ばかみたいに
遠回りしただけじゃない！
What is this?!  I was just sent on some wild goose chase!
ジェット 聞いてる？
Jet!  Are you listening?!
S-Stop, please...
や やめてくれよ
The grey ash is back.
グレイアッシュは戻ったんだから
いいだろ？
Come on, let him go.  I'm asking ya.
なあ 返してやってくれよ　頼むよ
Sorry to make you deliver it all the way here.
（ピカロ）わざわざ届けてくれて
すまなかったな
礼を言う
I give my thanks.
You!
こいつっ
早いとこ やっちまえ！
Get rid of him.  Quickly!
（フェイ）ピカロ･カルヴィーノ！
Piccaro Calvino!
Stay still!
おとなしくすんのよ！
もう少し上品にできねえのかよ
Can't she be a little more elegant?!
おい 殺すなよ
賞金パーにする気か？
Don't kill them!  Ya trying to kill our bounty?!
Bounty hunters?  Get that thing back, now!
ちっ 賞金稼ぎか
すぐにブツを取り戻せ！
どわあっ
ロコ！
Roco!
ええい！
ロコ！
くそうっ ばかが！ ううっ
Shit!  Idiots!
Really, you've caused me enough trouble.
（フェイ）
全く 手間かけさせてくれたわね
Come on, hang on!  You alive?!
（スパイク）おい しっかりしろ
生きてるか？
おい！
HEY!
うっ 師匠
さっきの見ててくれたか？
Master... did you... see that right... now?
よし もうしゃべるな
すぐに医者を呼んでくるからな
Yeah.  Don't speak anymore.  I'll call a doctor right now.
（ロコ）うおっ
（スパイク）おい！
Hey!
頼みがある
I have... a favor...
オルゴールの中に…
In... the music... box...
分かってる　ステラのことは任せろ
I know.  Leave Stella to me.
I trust you...
頼む
（スパイク）よし 待ってろ
いいか？ 死ぬな　死ぬなよ！
All right, hold on.  Now, don't die.  Don't die!
なあ
Hey... if I knew you... earlier...
あんたと
もっと早く知り合えてたら―
友達になれたかな？
Would we... have been... friends?
どうぞ
Come in.
ロコ？
Roco?
ロコでしょ？
It's you, Roco?
…の代理だ
I'm taking his place.
ああっ あなたでもいいわ　聞いて
You'll do.  You know what?
Roco got me some grey ash!
ロコがグレイアッシュを
手に入れてくれたの　手術代もよ
And the operation fees!
目が治るんだって！
They told me my eyes will be better!
Isn't it wonderful?  What should I do?
すごいわ　どうしよう
I want to see Roco first.
最初にロコの顔が見たいの
だから すぐ来てって伝えて
とにかく早くよ
So, tell him to come here right now!  To hurry over here!
まさか捕まったの？
Did he... get caught?
No...
（スパイク）いや
じゃあ どうしてロコは来ないの？
Then why isn't Roco coming?
He's dead, isn't he?
死んだのね
そう
I see...
（スパイク）ステラ
Stella.
いいの　もう帰って
It's all right...  Leave me.
分かってるの
I know.
Roco died because he did something bad, right?
ロコは 悪いことをしたから
死んだんでしょ？
お願い　今日はもう帰って
Please, leave me for today...
あたしは―
I...
一度もこの目で
ロコの姿を見られなかったわ
I never got to see Roco once with my own eyes...
ねえ 本当のロコは
どんなだったの？
Hey, what was Roco really like?
You know without looking, right?
（スパイク）
見えなくたって分かるだろ？
いいやつだったさ
He was a great guy.
Just like the one you knew...
あんたが知ってるとおりのな
Too much time has passed by...
Aishiteta to nageku niwa
...to lament that we were deeply in love.
Amarinimo toki wa sugite shimatta
The wind keeps blowing, while my heart...
Mada kokoro no hokorobi wo
...cannot heal all the tears in it.
lyasenu mama kaze ga fuiteru
Someone, cry for me with parched eyes.
Kawaita hitomi de dareka naite kure
The real folk blues.
The real folk blues
I only want to know what true sadness is.
Honto no kanashimi ga shiritai dake
Sitting in muddy water...
Doro no kawa ni tsukatta
...isn't such a bad life...
Jinsei mo waruku wa nai
...if it ends after the first time...
Ichido kiri de owaru nara
～
（エド）えー 来週から
エドが出まーす　ヘヘヘ
Starting next week, Ed will appear.
Wait, who are you?
（スパイク）
“ヘヘヘ”って 誰だ？ お前
Um...  Let me introduce myself.
（エド）えー 自己紹介します
Edward Wong Hau Pepelu Tivrusky the Fourth!
エドワード･ウォン･ハウ･
ペペル･チブルスキー４世だよ
That's a long name...
（スパイク）なっげえ名前だな
（フェイ）誰よ こいつ
Who the hell is this?
I made that name up myself!  Isn't it cool?
（エド）名前は自分でつけました
かっこいーい
（スパイク）
いや 大体 ４世って何だよ
First of all, what do you mean "the Fourth"?
Next Episode: Jamming with Edward!
（エド）次回「ジャミング･
ウィズ･エドワード」
So, anyway... who is this kid?
（ジェット）
あー ところで この子 誰なんだ？
Watch it!
（エド）見てねー